Muhammad Ali

MEAN | MERN Stack Developer

Passionate, responsible and committed developer with a get-it-done, on-time spirit, and more than 4 years of experience in implementing and adapting technically sophisticated online web applications. Capable of writing pixel perfect web applications with strong expertise in Javascript MV* frameworks like AngularJS / Angular / ReactJS / NodeJS.

e aliiqbal208@gmail.com m +92 300 2081994 w aliiqbal208.com ln linkedin g github

Work Experience

MERN Stack Developer Arthur Technologies

04/ 2020 - Present

Responsibilities

- Develop the React.js pages and shared components.
- Implement rich functions in various pages: form validations, crud, grid list, search, server side sort, server side pagination, multiselection, authentication, custom form fields, components, etc.
- Design a scalable web architecture, as well as the APIs to support it continuously.
- Use Redux to build User Interface, have strong knowledge of state store, middleware, action creator, reducer and container.
- Use Node.js and Express to build web server and Restful APIs.
- Optimizing app components and improving the product's performance.
- Focus on performance, usability and up-to-date practices.
- Follow the Scrum/Agile development methodologies.
- Extensively used GIT for version controlling and regularly pushed the code to GitHub.

Environment:

HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Less, JavaScript, TailwindCss, Ajax, React.js, Redux, Redux-saga, Axios,MongoDB,AWS, JSON, Github, Restful API, AWS, JIRA, Visual studio Code, NPM, Eslint, Chrome Developer Tools, Robomongo, Postman, ES5, ES6, Webpack, Mongoose and Node.js.

Angular Developer 01/2018 - 04/2020 TazteqPk

Worked as Angular developer on cloud based ERP called INTTEO.

Responsibilities

 Develop ERP user interface according to PSD's.

- Develop Common components / Pipes / Directives that are used in every modules with latest code standards.
- Develop ERP modules maintaining best code practices.
- Write tests using framework (Ex. Jasmine).
- Integrate the Java Based API's with ERP different modules and ensure the best efficiency of application.
- Involved in daily stand up meetings and Coordinated with QA team, used Scrum / Agile methodologies for software development.

Environment:

HTML5, CSS3, Less, JavaScript, TypeScript, Ajax, JSON, Bitbucket, Restful API, JIRA, Jasmine, Visual studio Code, NPM, Eslint, ES5, ES6, Angular, Angular Material, Sourcetree, Jenkins, Karma, RxJS and Chrome Developer Tools.

Angular Developer 05/ 2017 – 01/ 2018 Whitehats

Worked as front end Angular 5 developer on web app similar to fiverr.com mainly targeted for UAE and Middle East countries called Maharati.

Responsibilities

- Build a pixel perfect application using Angular5.
- Integrate PHP API's with Angular with the co-ordination of Backend team.
- Develop components in angular that application module use them and work efficiently.
- Ensure high performance of the application in IOS/Android/ Windows.
- Fix identified bugs by QA department.

Environment:

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, Ajax, JSON, Bitbucket, JIRA, Visual studio Code, NPM, Eslint, ES5, ES6, Angular, Angular Material, Sourcetree, RxJS and Chrome Developer Tools.

Project Links

• https://www.maharati.com

AngularJS Developer EchnoTech IT Solutions

05/2016 - 05/2017

Responsibilities

- Develop new features in their existing cloud based survey Web Apps.
- Front End Development using HTML5, CSS3, Angular JS and jQuery.
- Resolve bugs in their existing code by analyzing and learn the already existing logic of code.
- Develop one page websites in AngularJS.
- Testing and validating work produced as part of the development process.
- Integrating backend web API's written in PHP Code laravel, CodeIgniter and ROR.
- Persist AngularJS style guide.
- API's development in ROR and Asp.Net MVC framework.
- Develop user interface for iPhone, iPad and Desktop.

Environment:

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, JSON, Bitbucket, Trello, Visual studio Code, NPM, AngularJS, AngularJS Material, Sourcetree, SVN, Chrome Developer Tools, ROR, FileZilla.

Project Links

• http://machotracker.com/EmiratesGuide/EG/demo/

Professional Training

Career Prep Fellowship 10/ 2016 - 01/ 2017 Amal Academy

Amal Academy is an education startup funded by Stanford University that teaches professional skills to students and corporations. During my training, I learned communication, leadership, problem solving and teamwork.

Technical Skills

Languages: Javascript, Typescript, C#, C++, C
Web: JavaScript, JQuery, ReactJS, AngularJS,
Angular, Angular Material, Mongoose, Node.js,
ROR, Redux, Gulp, Grunt, NPM, Eslint, ES5,
ES6, Webpack, Express.js, RxJS, ASP.NET Web
API, MVC, XML, DataStructure, JSON, AJAX,
JSON, JWT, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap,
Tailwindcss, Less, SCSS, REST, Entity
Framework, RESTful Web Services, MVC
Architecture.

Operating systems: Windows (2000, XP, 7, 8,10)

 $\textbf{Databases:} \ MySQL, MongoDB, SQL \ Server.$

Testing: Jasmine, Karma, Mocha, Chai, Chrome

Developer Tools.

IDE/Tools: Sublime, Microsoft Visual Studio, SQL Management Studio, WebStorm, Postman, Fiddler, FileZilla, Robomongo, SQLyog, Navicat, Apache Server, Sourcetree, GitHub, Tortoise SVN, Slack, Trello, JIRA, Notepad++, Atom.

Version Control: Git, Bitbucket, TFS. **Methodologies:** Agile Scrums, Waterfall

Education

BS Computer Science

2011 - 2015

University of Lahore

CGPA: 3.45

FSc (Pre-Engg) 2009 – 2011

Govt. Islamia College, Civil Lines, Lahore.

Marks: 71% Languages English | Urdu

Interests and Capabilities

Computer Algorithms | Gym | Running | Problem solving | Fast & long learner | Self Motivated | Good Communication Skills | Tech blog reader